

Michael Panco
Frontend Web Developer
www.micpanco.com

+639682305982 / +639776336055 micpanco@gmail.com Cainta Rizal, Philippines

A resourceful, self-motivated, talented web developer with over **13 years of working experience** in delivering web projects to a high standard. I have a proven track record of providing delightful UI design, accurate details, and effective user experience. My technical toolkit includes advanced proficiency in JavaScript and mastery of performance testing tools and techniques.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Frontend Developer

Sept 2022 - PRESENT

Trainalta / Encora

- Developed interactive timetable for client's gym profile programs.
- Enhance the gym page user interface to make it more appealing.
- Led the successful development of the Earnportal with the latest NextJS.
- Collaborated with other developers, designers, and project teams to ensure a successful result

Fullstack Web Developer

Nov 2021 - Aug 2022

Vokke / GetDevs

- Refactored existing applications, cutting development time by 30% while ensuring performance standings.
- Led the successful frontend development from start to finish
- Improved user experience resulting in customer satisfaction.
- Collaborated with other developers, designers, and project teams to ensure a successful result

Freelance Web Developer

Jan 2020 – Oct 2021

Property Investment Inc.

- Developed the product CRM, and introduced all the cutting-edge tools to make the project compete with product competitors.
- Integrate marketing tools to track user product engagement.
- Contribute ideas especially on UI and UX to make it more appealing for t and easy to use.

Senior Web Developer

Sep 2015 - Dec 2019

Bizme Solutions

- Pioneered the overall project classesa2z.com from managing the server, building the user interface, and backend creation.
- Mentored 3 junior developers in software development processes.
- Facilitated integration of third-party services like Stripe and other APIs to satisfy customer's needs.
- Communicate with the project owner to ensure the functionalities are adequately adapted.

Web Developer Software Developer Junior Web Developer Bona88 Casino Mobile Ventures Inc. PH Offshore Inc. Jan 2015 – Jul 2015 Jun 2012 – Dec 2014 Jan 2010 – May 2012

SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

- React / NextJS
- React Native
- Strapi / Contentful
- MaterialUI / Tailwind / ShadCN UI
- NodeJS / ExpressJS / NestJS
- Figma Design Conversion
- Mobile-first Development Practices
- Cross Browser
 Compatibility
- Algolia / Elasticsearch
- Adobe Photoshop
- GIT
- Web Performance Optimization
- Agile and Scrum
- Command Line Tools

SOFT SKILLS

- Teamwork
- Works well under pressure
- Willingness to try new things
- Learning agility
- Resilience
- Problem Solving
- Creativity

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science – 2009 Navotas Polytechnic College, Navotas City, Philippines

PERSONAL DETAILS

Gender: Male

Age: 36

Date of Birth: June 26, 1988

Civil Status: Married